- My
Speaker 1: curiosity is piqued a little bit because I'm just wondering, from your vantage point,
I kind of forgot where I
Speaker 1: was going with that. I'm just trying to think like, where do you,
Speaker 1: - Oh yeah, now I remember. Okay, so we go back during the birtherism issue that Trump was sort of the main propagator, sort of pushing the idea that Obama was from Kenya or some other country, and then we kind of go forward a little bit to the lock her up chants about Hillary Clinton during his first campaign.
Speaker 1: all of it's like building hype, you know, like building this, like, you know, this populist energy behind like, oh yeah, we should, we should look into this. We should, you know, totally go into it. And then like he postulates the 2020 election fraud. And then with his most recent campaign, you know, he makes this big hyped up, you know, promise or his surrogates do that they're going to release the Epstein files. And I'm wondering if you think that there's a through line between all of that type of behavior, because at the end, at the end of the,
you
Speaker 1: know like looking at all that myself i
see it
Speaker 1: as these completely separate cons but but they're but they're all in and and and like on their face like they're they're ways to sort of con people into getting getting more support for you essentially it's like we're gonna we're gonna con them by telling that the president's not from this country we're gonna con them by saying that we're gonna lock up hillary but never do it we're gonna con them by telling them the election's stolen we're gonna con them by saying we're gonna release the epstein files and it's gonna be this this massive exposure that's gonna implicate all these dumb Democrats.
Speaker 1: things like that and to me i just think that like if you're a realist about this and i'm saying this as somebody who voted for trump twice that people need to realize that he sort of like effectuates uh galvanizes people through his empty promises and or empty claims and such and so i'm just wondering it's like if you're like one of these people like rokhana or if you're another one of these like democrats you know like ted lu who's like you know throwing all these kind of baseless accusations around about what
the former president
Speaker 1: the president did when he was younger and none of it has any sort of like provable
Speaker 2: evidence. Like, why are these people going along with the con that he was sort of participant to?
-
Speaker 3: Well,
Speaker 4: I think that-- - If you reject the premise, you can do that too.
Speaker 3: - Yeah, I think the
Speaker 5: complicating factor is that Trump really never brought up the Epstein files or Epstein issue on his own volition. You would occasionally be asked about it.
Speaker 5: Yeah, his surrogates did, but Trump himself never really did. He would occasionally be asked about it, and he would be noncommittal. He would say, yeah, maybe, I don't know, there could be some phony stuff in there.
Then you
Speaker 5: have Kash Patel and Dan Bongino and others who are banging the drums on it.
And it
Speaker 5: played into a narrative that I think was specific to 2024, more so
than really
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): having precursors in the lock-her-up chants and...
so
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): forth or the election fraud stuff I mean I guess you could always try to like weave together a narrative that connects these disparate sort of phases in the Trump you
Speaker 8: know phenomenon I mean
Speaker 9: I'm not in 2024 there was this whole conceit
Speaker 10: where like Trump was
gathering like this
Speaker 10: Avengers squad to take down the deep state so he and RFK Jr and Tulsi Gabbard
Speaker 11: and Joe Rogan and Elon Musk were all gonna like
Speaker 11: join hands and destroy the deep state once and for all whatever that meant i mean it was like basically as realistic as a marvel movie um and
so the
Speaker 11: idea was that no trump in taking on the deep state was also by by extension necessarily going to be exposed the epstein uh he's necessarily always also by extension somehow necessarily going to be exposing the epstein perpetrators or releasing the Epstein files or whatever, and then he tied
in all the
Speaker 11: Also, putting out the JFK files, I mean, that was maybe a story for a half
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): a day last year. And then everybody, I guess, stopped caring about it, even though that was used as this campaign talking point by way of Robert F. Kennedy Jr. And there was a lot of hype around it, but it seemed to fizzle pretty quick. Or releasing, like, I don't know, UFO stuff or whatever. It's just like, what was one way for him to galvanize support...
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): and for the
Speaker 11: Republicans in general, to galvanize support and harness the energy from this quote-unquote "anti-establishment" online demographic,
which is kind of
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): ideologically inchoate, but was more conducive to the Republicans in 2024. Because, you know, there was a way in which Trump had been sort of beleaguered by some of the permanent bureaucracy factions,
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): Especially in his first term where he was hobbled by the Mueller investigation and by just this constant drip, drip, drip of leaks about how some little snippet of information was supposed to be the smoking gun showing that he had colluded with Russia or what have you.
And then
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): he was prosecuted.
I
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): think largely scurrilously when he was out of office, so during the interregnum period, where this sort of narrative could be set up that he was in opposition to these deep-seated, quote, deep-stated interests. So I think that got all kind
Speaker 11: of conflated with the Epstein story
in a way.
Which
Speaker 11: was always odd because like Donald Trump himself really was like pals with Jeffrey Epstein for quite a few years. He knew Ghislaine Maxwell when he was first asked about Ghislaine Maxwell's indictment
and arrest in
Speaker 11: 2020. You can go find the clip.
He says
Speaker 11: something like,
I wish her
Speaker 11: well. And then he's asked about it again like a month later. And he says,
if they say she's
Speaker 11: guilty of something, let them prove it. Like he's clearly...
not
Speaker 11: buying it or he's clearly skeptical that she actually is guilty of what they say she was guilty of, which would stand to reason given his firsthand knowledge of both Epstein and Maxwell. But, you
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): know, these right wing podcast guys like Cash Patel and Bongino and the others in that orbit who are just like so flamboyantly, uh,
calling
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): for the release of Epstein files so they
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): thought that it was going to take down the Democratic deep state donor class or something like that. They were just as deluded as anybody else in terms of their understanding of the underlying facts and evidence on this thing. But it is an irony that
they're
Speaker 12 (lower-pitched voice): the ones who are responsible for foregrounding this issue in the first place. I mean, if they just shut up, then like probably
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): we would be talking about something else right now, but like they had to charge into office and demand like some reckoning with the Epstein files, which I'm fine with. I'm enjoying it,
but
Speaker 11: like it's probably, I don't even understand how it's tenable for Cash Patel to stay as FBI director. If he literally as a private citizen was denouncing the previous FBI director as concealing a list of pedophiles,
and then
Speaker 11: he becomes fbi director and says whoops no list of pedophiles
like
Speaker 5: obviously the average person who hears about that is going to think themselves wait what there must be something that they're covering up
this is
Speaker 5: crazy um now if you have a more
extensive
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): understanding of the actual facts and evidence you might not have
that first
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): blush reaction but i
Speaker 14: don't blame the average person for having something
like that as
Speaker 14: their reaction to such a ridiculous quote flip flop so because
a
Speaker 15: lot of them were the ones that were watching those podcasters say those things online so yeah i get i get the point